A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Economic Development Administration, Program Files of William P. Gormbley FA529
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Economic Development Administration, Program Files of William P. Gormbley
1953-1968
Rockefeller Archive Center
Gormbley, William P.
Ford Foundation
FA529
2.62 Cubic Feet 2 standard record storage boxes.
Conditions Governing Access note
Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Arrangement
As received.
Scope and Contents
Contains: grant appropriation summaries, program and project reports, and abstracts.
- Grants Appropriation Summaries (1/2), Oct 1953 (Box 1)
- Grants Appropriation Summaries (2/2), Oct 1953 (Box 1)
- Grant and Appropriations Summaries -- Table of Contents and Aphabetical Index, Oct 1953 (Box 1)
- Grant and Appropriations Summaries -- Vol. 1 -- International A-H, Oct 1953 (Box 1)
- Grant and Appropriations Summaries -- Vol. 2 -- International I and J, Oct 1953 (Box 1)
- Grant and Appropriations Summaries -- Vol. 3 -- International K and L, Oct 1953 (Box 1)
- Grant and Appropriations Summaries -- Vol. 4 -- Free Institutions -- Economic Well-Being -- Education -- Behavioral Sciences -- Michigan Committee Projects, Oct 1953 (Box 1)
- Grant Summaries -- EDA Budget, 1957 (Box 1)
- EDA Business Conferences, 1957-1961 (Box 1)
- Committee for Economic Development, 1964 (Box 1)
- Corporate Management Development Program -- General Electric, 1963 (Box 1)
- Corporate Management Development Program -- IBM (Box 1)
- GCT -- Terminal Aid to Business Education, 1962-1964 (Box 1)
- General Electric Co. -- Meetings on Educational Relations Activities (between Industries and Foundations), 1963 (Box 1)
- International Marketing Institute (James Hagler), 1963-1965 (Box 1)
- Projects -- Mathematics in Business School Curriculum, 1962-1963 (Box 1)
- Projects -- Programmed Learning for Business (University of Michigan -- Odiorne) (Box 1)
- Abstracts Projects, 1964-1966 (Box 2)
- Abstracts 1968 (Box 2)
- Abstracts 67-400--67-602, 1967 (Box 2)
- Abstracts 67-200--67-399, 1967 (Box 2)
- Abstracts 67-1--67-199, 1967 (Box 2)
- Abstracts 66-267--66-423, 1966 (Box 2)
- Abstracts 66-1--66-266, 1966 (Box 2)
- Abstracts 64-303--1965, 1964-1965 (Box 2)
- Abstracts 1963-64-301, 1963-1964 (Box 2)
- Abstracts Deleted, 1965 (Box 2)